Guide to the Bradford Edward Ableson Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1978-2009; Series IV
  - Biographical Documentation
    - Chronological Sequence
      - Marriage Certificate (photocopy), 1986 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Veterans Educational Assistance Act of 1984 (GI Bill) Application, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Desert Storm, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Groton-New London Navy Chaplain Team, 1993-1996 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - The Divinity School, Yale University, Class of 1985, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Holiday Letter, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - The Commencement Service of Columbia Theological Seminary, 1999 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - USAF Academy Basic Freefall Parachuting Program, AM-490, 2000 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - College of Naval Warfare Class of 2002 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Travel Orders, 2002-2004 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - USS George Washington; includes CD containing miscellaneous files from BEA's computer, Jul 2002-Mar 2004 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - National Defense University, Joint Forces Staff College, Class 04-2, Graduation Exercise, 25 Jun 2004 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Application-Diocese of Kentucky, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Yale Summer Scholarly Exchange Program for Religious Leaders Gulf and Middle East Region, 2008 (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Memorial Blog Post, by George E. Packard, 17 Feb 2009 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Obituaries, Yale Divinity School News, USAO News and Events, 18,21 Feb 2009 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - The Early Life of Bradford E. Ableson (brief version) by Juanise Ableson Stockdale (BEA's mother), 31 Mar 2009 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - The Early Life of Bradford E. Ableson Birth to Age 18, by Juanise Ableson Stockdale, 24 Apr 2009 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Program and photographs from dedication ceremony of Bradford E. Ableson Memorial Library, USS George Washington (CVN-73), 2009 Sep 22 (Box 10, Folder 22A)
        The Bradford E. Ableson Memorial Library comprises the media center, lounge, and library and is visited by 900 Navy personnel daily.
    - Military Service Records
      - U.S. Navy Officer Service Record, 1984-2004 (Box 10, Folder 23-26)
      - U.S. Navy Officer Service Record, 1984-2004 (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
      - U.S. Navy Quarterly Reports, 1989-1996 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - U.S. Navy Physical Fitness Record, 1984-2002 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Awards and Certificates
      - Certificates and Awards, 1984-2008 (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Citations, 1986-2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - U.S. Navy Personal Award Recommendations, 1988, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Defense Superior Service Medal for Exceptionally Meritorious Service for the Armed Forces of the United States, award and citation, photograph, 29 Jun 2007 (Box 11, Folder 9A)
      - University of Science and Arts of Oklahoma, Centennial Homecoming Program, Bradford Ableson inducted into Hall of Fame, 2008 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Conferences and Programs Attended
      - 1992 National Prayer Breakfast, 12 Mar 1992 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - The Ethical Use of Force: The Responsibility to Intervene, 15-16 Nov 1993 (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Menninger Suicide Awareness and Prevention, Mar 1994 (Box 11, Folder 13-15)
      - USS Columbia SSN 771 Commissioning, 9 Oct 1995 (Box 11, Folder 16)
      - Integrity Task Force: Character is Destiny, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 1-3)
      - Ethics and Leadership, 16-17 Nov 1998 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - The Joseph A. Reich, Sr. Distinguished Lecture on War, Morality, and the Military Profession, 18 Nov 1998 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - Student Guide for Airmanship 490 Basic Freefall Parachuting, 1 May 1999 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - Generation X Presentation Notes, Jan 2000 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - The Arc of Instability: Challenges for U.S. Policy & Strategy in the Greater Middle East, 6-7 Mar 2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - Human Factors in Conflict Management, Nov 2002 (Box 12, Folder 9-10)
      - Department of Defense, Care for Victims of Sexual Assault Conference, 20-24 Sep 2004 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - The Navy Chaplain Corps Strategic Communications, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 12-14)
      - Critical Incident Stress Training, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - 3D MAW Awards Seminar, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Photographs
      - Portraits (includes negatives) (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Memorial Video Presentation Capt Bradford E. Ableson 02 Jan 1959-17 Feb 2009 (includes photos of Bradford Ableson and family) (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Life Events, including CD of images from BEA ordination rehearsal (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Official Military Photos Performing Various Sacraments for the US Navy, 1988-2008 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Playing Hockey, 10 Mar 1994 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Receiving Camp David Award (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Submarines (signed photos) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Memorabilia
    - Poem: "One Day at a Time", by Buddy Ableson (BEA's father) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Identification Cards, 1984, 1985, 1999, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - 100th Yale Harvard Football Game Program and Newspaper Clippings, Nov 1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Yale Divinity School Student Directory, 1984-1985 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Camp David stationery, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Change of Command Ceremony Programs, 1987-2000 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Ephemera (including post cards, programs, brochures), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
    - Bradford E. Ableson's naval uniform (Box OV14)
    - Desert Storm Liturgical Stole (handmade), 1991 (Box OV14)
    - Photograph: Yale Divinity School Class of 1985 (Box OV14)
    - Plaques from Various Duty Stations (Box OV15, Box 16)
- Subject Files, Series V
  - Accommodation Issues (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - After Action Reports (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Alcoholism (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Articles (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Awards Information (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Battle Shock (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Bible Study (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Bible Study Outlines (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Billet Justifications (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Biography (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Blended Families (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Briefings (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - CACO (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Catholic Lay Eucharist Service (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Chaplain (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Church/CHC File (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Classics (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
  - Combat Stress Briefing (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Command Religious Programs (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Common Navy Acronyms and Terms (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Confirmation Materials (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Conscientious Objection (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Critical Incident Stress Training (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Currents (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Death (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Depression Stress (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Domestic Violence (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Emergency/Privation Issues (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Ethics (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Family (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Family Advocacy Program (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Family Assistance Contact Team (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Fraternization (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Funerals (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
  - Generational: Boomers vs. Busters (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Grief (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Gulf War Materials (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Heritage (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Hockey (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Immigration and Naturalization Information (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Instructions (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Items of Interest (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Joint Ministry (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Landmines (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Marriage Materials (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Medal of Honor (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Memoranda (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Mentoring (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Mess Bill Receipts (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Mission Guidance (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Model of Ministry (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Morale (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Naval Order of the United States (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Naval Support Facility (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Navy Chaplain Foundation, Inc. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Newsletters/USN (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Ombudsman (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Planned Ministry Objectives (PMO) (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Prayer Breakfasts (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Prayers (Box 20, Folder 13-14)
  - Predeployment (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Recruiting (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Reports of Chaplaincy (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Reserve Chaplain Program (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - SUBRON 2 CRP Brief (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Suicide Prevention (Box 20, Folder 20-23)
  - Suicide Prevention Model Brief (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Tasking File (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Two Bell Ceremony (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Uniforms/Personal Equipment (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - USS Mars (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Welcome Aboard (Box 21, Folder 6)
- Resources, Series VI
  - Naval Chaplaincy Resources
    - Books, Pamphlets, and Manuscripts
      - Armed Forces 2002 Sexual Harassment Survey, by Rachel Lipari and Anita R. Lancaster (Box 21)
      - Book of Worship for United States Forces, by the Armed Forces Chaplains Board (Box 21)
      - Chaplain's Handbook: Guidelines for Ministry & Worship for Chaplains Endorsed by the Bishop Suffragan for Chaplaincies, by the Episcopal Church (Box 21)
      - Courage Under Fire: Epictetus's Doctrines in a Laboratory of Human Behavior, by James Bond Stockdale (Box 21)
      - The Fleet Religious Support Activity, by Lieutenant Stephen O. Wallace, CHC, USNR (Box 21)
      - For All Who Go Down to the Sea in Ships, Office of the Chief of Naval Operations (Box 21)
      - History of the Chaplain Corps, U.S. Navy, Vol. X, Biographies 1982-1991 (Box 21)
      - Marriage and Military Life for Dating and Married Couples (Box 22)
      - Military-Civilian Teamwork in Suicide Prevention, by Meyer Moldeven (Box 22)
      - Military Funerals (Box 22)
      - New Naval Chaplains and Their Spouses (Box 22)
      - A Prayer Book for the Armed Services (Box 22)
      - Preaching, Chaplain Resource Board (Box 22)
      - Program Perspectives on Suicide Prevention: Guidelines for Chaplains (Box 22)
      - The Story of the United States Coast Guard Memorial Chapel, The United States Coast Guard Academy (Box 22)
      - Task Force Report on Care for Victims of Sexual Assault, April 2004, U.S. Department of Defense (Box 22)
      - There is Hope: A Chaplain's Manual for Suicide Prevention, LCDR Thomas W.S. Logan, Jr., CHC, USNR (Box 22)
      - World Religions: A Resource for U.S. Army Chaplains and Chaplain Assistants (Box 22)
    - Periodicals and Articles
      - The Military Chaplain, 2002, 2008 (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - The Navy Chaplain, 1983, 1991, 1993, 1997-1999 (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - Naval Chaplain Resources - Articles (Box 23, Folder 3-5)
  - Military Resources
    - Manuscript - The Ethics of the Movement for Nuclear Disarmament in Historical Perspective, by Kurt Pfotenhauer, 9 May 1985 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Articles pertaining to the Military, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Military Newsletters, 1992-2002 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Navy Recruiting Materials, 1985, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Ministry Resources
    - Augsburg Sermons 3: Gospels, Series A (Box 24)
    - Beyond the Headlines, by Gordon Thiessen (Box 24)
    - The Book of Occasional Services 2003 (Box 24)
    - God is One: The Way of Islam (Box 24)
    - Islam: Between Ignorant Followers and Incapable Scholars, by Abdul Quader Audah (Box 24)
    - Living in a Troubled World: Selections from the Writings of William C. Menninger, MD (Box 24)
    - Ministry with the Sick (Box 24)
    - Mixing Religion and Politics, by William Muehl (Box 24)
    - A "New and Improved" Jesus? Sermons for Lent and Easter, by Barbara Brokhoff (Box 24)
    - Object Lesson: Old Testament-Series A, by Edward C. Grube (Box 24)
    - Stories for the Journey, by William R. White (Box 24)
    - Why Preach? Why Listen?, by William Muehl (Box 24)
    - Wide Awake and Staring: Readings for 3:00 a.m., by Bruce Scott (Box 24)
    - Sermons and Speeches by others (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Sermon Resources (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
- Audio-visual Material, Series VII
  - Cassette Tapes and CDs
    - Robert C. Johnson "Christian Doctrine II", 12, 17 Apr 1984 (Box 25)
    - Beecher Lectures: William Muehl 1-4, 1985 (Box 25)
    - Seven Keys to a Happy Life, William C. Menninger, MD, 1988 (Box 25)
    - Maj. Gen. John Grinalds, Irvine Community Church, 13 Jul 1990 (Box 25)
    - Praise and Promise, 1991 (Box 25)
    - Chaplain Ableson Interview w/Barbara Witcher KBRT radio, 4 Jul 1992 (Box 25)
    - Psalm 150 "What Else Can We Do the Sunday After Easter?" Dr. Mouzon Biggs, Jr., Boston Avenue Church, Tulsa, OK, 23 Apr 1995 (Box 25)
    - William Barclay's Daily Study Bible Series: NT, 11 Jul 2000 (Box 25)
    - Coalition Strategic Alternatives, Prof. John English, 22 Feb 2002 (Box 25)
    - USS George Washington 2004 Cruise CD Operation IRAQI Freedom (Box 25)
    - A Biblical/Spiritual/Ecclesiological Reflection on General Convention by the Rev. Dr. Francis H. Wade, 2006 (Box 25)
    - Homiletics on CD, Jan-Feb 2007, May-Jun 2007 (Box 25)
    - Somebody's Prayin', The Flying W Wranglers, 2007 (Box 25)
    - Chief of Chaplains Continuing Education Tape prepared for U.S. Navy Chaplains, Dr. Robert Clyde Johnson, Dr. John Killinger, Fr. Francis S. MacNutt (2 tapes) (Box 25)
    - Dr. Peter Marshall's Sermons, n.d. (Box 25)
    - Charlton Heston Presents "The Word" Audio Series, 1997 (Box OV26)
  - Video Tapes
    - The Conversion of Colonel Bottomly, 1985 (Box OV26)
    - Hidden Keys to Loving Relationships: The Gary Smalley Series 1-3, 5-8 (2 copies of tape 2, does not include tape 4), 1993 (Box OV26)